Finding Aid for the Mischa Schneider Collection of Test Pressing Recordings, circa 1940-1980
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Recordings issued by Marlboro Recording Society, circa 1970-1980, II.; Item 30-45
  - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 32, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Marlboro Recording Society: MRS-3, 1970-1979 Side 1 matrix: MRS 3A (34276); Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: unknown Serenade completed on Side 2. (Box 1, Item 32)
    Transcribed title: Introduction and variations, op. 160
    Performers: Paula Robison, flute; Rudolf Serkin, piano
  - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 33, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Marlboro Recording Society: MRS-4, 1970 Side 1 matrix: MRS-4A RE-1 (27493); Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: unknown Printed label (Box 1, Item 33)
    Work number: 33_01
    Trios, oboes, English horn, op. 87, C major
    Transcribed title: Trio in C major, op. 87
    Performers: John Mack, Joseph Turner, oboes; Patricia Grignet, English horn
    Work number: 33_02
    Variations, piano trio, op. 44, E♭ major
    Transcribed title: Variations in Eb major, op. 44
    Performers: Hidetaro Suzuki, violin; Ronald Leonard, cello; Rudolf Serkin, piano
  - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 34, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Marlboro Recording Society: MRS-5, 1970-1979 Side 1 matrix: MRS-5A (30548); Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: unknown Label: "Test pressing" (Box 1, Item 34)
    Work number: 34_01
    Nielsen, Carl, 1865-1931
    Quintets, winds, op. 43
    Transcribed title: Wind quintet
    Performers: Paula Robison, flute; Joseph Turner, oboe; Larry Combs, clarinet; William Winstead, bassoon; Richard Solis, horn
    Work number: 34_02
    Weber, Carl Maria von, 1786-1826
    Quintet, clarinet, violins, viola, cello, op. 34, B♭ major
    Transcribed title: Clarinet quintet
    Performers: Harold Wright, clarinet; Vera Beths, Mari Tsumura, violins; Philipp Naegele, viola; Jeffrey Solow, cello
  - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 35, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Marlboro Recording Society: MRS-5, 1970-1979 Side 1 matrix: MRS-5A -1A; Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Pitman Date of recording: unknown Label: "Test pressing" (Box 1, Item 35)
    Work number: 35_01
    Transcribed title: Wind 5
    Work number: 35_02
    Transcribed title: Clar. 5
  - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 36, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Marlboro Recording Society: MRS-6, 1971 Side 1 matrix: MRS-6A-1A; Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Pitman Date of recording: unknown Sleeve: "9/24/71" (Box 1, Item 36)
    Work number: 36_01
    Trios, strings, op. 9, no. 1
    Transcribed title: String trio G major
    Performers: Isidore Cohen, violin; Nobuko Imai, viola; Nathaniel Rosen, cello
    Work number: 36_02
    Quartets, piano, strings, WoO 36
    Transcribed title: Piano quartet C maj.
    Performers: Rudolf Serkin, piano; Felix Galimir, violin; Nobuko Imai, viola, Nathaniel Rosen, cello
  - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 37, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Marlboro Recording Society: MRS-6, 1971 Side 1 matrix: MRS-6A (30276); Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: unknown Label: "Arizona pressing"; Lead-out groove: "JB", "MO#2" (Box 1, Item 37)
    Work number: 37_01
    Work number: 37_02
    Transcribed title: Piano quartet C major
  - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 38, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Marlboro Recording Society: MRS-7, 1977? Side 1 matrix: MRS-7-1 (24813); Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: unknown Label: "test pressing"; "1-8-75" (Box 1, Item 38)
    Work number: 38_01
    Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809
    Trios, piano, flute, cello, H. XV, 15, G major
    Transcribed title: Flute trio
    Performers: Rudolf Serkin, piano; Michel Debost, flute; Peter Wiley, cello
    Work number: 38_02
    Trios, piano, clarinet, cello, op. 11, B♭ major
    Transcribed title: Clar. Trio, op. 11
    Performers: Rudolf Serkin, piano; Richard Stoltzman, clarinet; Alain Meunier, cello
  - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 39, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Marlboro Recording Society: MRS-8, 1975-1979? Side 1 matrix: MRS-8-1 (24814); Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: unknown Label: "Test Pressing" (Box 1, Item 39)
    Work number: 39_01
    Serenades, K. 375, E♭ major. (2d version)
    Transcribed title: Wind serenade
    Performers: Eric Arbiter, Alexander Heller, bassoons; Frank Cohen, Richard Stoltzman, clarinets; Robert Routch, John Serkin, horns; Richard Woodhams, Rudolph Vrbsky, oboes
    Work number: 39_02
    Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893
    Petite symphonie
    Transcribed title: Petit symphonie
    Performers: Paul Dunkel, flute; Rudolph Vrbsky, Allan Vogel, oboes; Frank Cohen, John Fullam, clarinets; Alexander Heller, Vincent Ellin, bassoons; Robert Routch, E. Scott Brubaker, horns
  - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 40, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Marlboro Recording Society: MRS-10, 1977 Side 1 matrix: MRS-10A (28568); Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: unknown Label: "Test pressing" (Box 2, Item 40)
    Work number: 40_01
    Quintets, guitar, violins (2), viola, violoncello, G. 451, E minor
    Transcribed title: Quintet in E minor for guitar and strings, G. 451
    Performers: David Starobin, guitar; Pina Carmirelli, Philip Setzer, violins; Philipp Naegele, viola; Peter Wiley, cello
    Work number: 40_02
    Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937
    Chansons madécasses
    Transcribed title: Chan-Mad
    Performers: Katherine Ciesinski, mezzo-soprano, Judith Mendenhall, flute, Paul Tobias, cello, Luis Batlle, piano
    Work number: 40_03
    Sonatas, bassoon, violoncello, K. 292, B♭ major
    Transcribed title: Bassoon son.
    Performers: Alexander Heller, bassoon, Yo-Yo Ma, cello
  - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 41, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Marlboro Recording Society: MRS-11, 1970-1976? Side 1 matrix: MRS-11A (29176); Side 2 matrix: MRS-11B (29176) Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: unknown Label: "Test Pressing" (Box 2, Item 41)
    Work number: 41_01
    Serenades, K. 361, B♭ major
    Transcribed title: Gran partita
    Performers: Instrumentalists from the Marlboro Music Festival; Marcel Moyse, conductor
  - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 42, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Marlboro Recording Society: MRS 12, 1976? Side 1 matrix: MRS-12-1 (29648); Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: unknown Label: "Test pressing" (Box 2, Item 42)
    Work number: 42_01
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750
    Canons, BWV 1087
    Transcribed title: Aria
    Performers: Rudolf Serkin, piano, with instrumental ensemble
    Work number: 42_02
    Sonatas, clarinet, piano, no. 3, op. 107, B♭ major
    Transcribed title: Clar. Son.
    Performers: David Singer, clarinet; Rudolf Serkin, piano
  - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 43, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Marlboro Recording Society: MRS 12, 1976? Side 1 matrix: MRS-12-1 (29648); Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: unknown Label: "Test pressing" (Box 2, Item 43)
    Work number: 43_01
    Transcribed title: Canons (from sleeve)
    Work number: 43_02
    Transcribed title: Clarinet sonata (from sleeve)
  - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 44, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Marlboro Recording Society: MRS-13, 1980? Side 1 matrix: none; Side 2 matrix: MRS-13B-RE-2 Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: unknown Label: "Test pressing" Label on side 1 bears crossed out inscription "Dumky Trio". The side contains 5 tracks of unidentified popular music. (Box 2, Item 44)
    Work number: 44_01
    Trios, piano, strings, op. 90, E minor. Movement 4-5
    Transcribed title: End of Dumky
    Performers: Bruno Canino, piano; Daniel Phillips, violin; Jerry Grossman, cello
    Work number: 44_02
    Quintets, guitar, violins, viola, violoncello, G. 449, D major
    Transcribed title: Guitar 5
    Performers: David Starobin, guitar; Pina Carmirelli, Joseph Genualdi, violins; Philipp Naegele, viola; Marcy Rosen, cello
  - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 45, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Marlboro Recording Society: MRS-13, 1980? Side 1 matrix: MRS-13-A-RE-1; Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: unknown Label: "Test pressing" Dumky trio completed on Side 2. (Box 2, Item 45)
    Work number: 45_01
    Trios, piano, strings, op. 90, E minor
    Transcribed title: Dumky trio beg.
    Work number: 45_02
    Transcribed title: Guitar quintet
- Recordings issued by other labels and an unpublished recording, circa 1970-1980, III.; Item 46-51
  Arranged in alphabetical order by manufacturer name and then by publisher number. The one unpublished item is at the end of the sequence.
  - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 46, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Heliodor: 2549-004 (Wergo 60036), 197-? Side 1 matrix: 25-49004B-1A (HEL 90038); Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Sonic Recording Products (Holbrook, NY) Date of recording: unknown RL ss Stamp on label: August 1969 (Box 2, Item 46)
    Work number: 46_03
    Webern, Anton, 1883-1945
    Kleine stücke
    Transcribed title: Webern
    Performers: Siegfried Palm, cello; Aloys Kontarsky, piano
    Work number: 46_01
    Ligeti, György, 1923-2006
    Concertos, cello, orchestra
    Transcribed title: Ligeti
    Performers: Siegfried Palm, cello; Hessian Radio Symphony; Michael Gielen, conductor
    Work number: 46_02
    Penderecki, Krzysztof, 1933-
    Sonatas, cello, orchestra
    Transcribed title: Penderecki
    Performers: Siegfried Palm, cello; Poznan Philharmonic; Andzej Markowski, conductor
    Work number: 46_04
    Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963
    Sonatas, cello, op. 25, no. 3
    Transcribed title: Hindemith
    Performers: Siegfried Palm, cello
    Work number: 46_05
    Zimmermann, Bernd Alois, 1918-1970
    Sonatas, cello
    Transcribed title: Zimmermann
  - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 47, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: His Master's Voice (RCA Red Seal): LHMV 13, 1955 Side 1 matrix: E4RP 0390; Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: unknown Looks like commercial release rather than test pressing. (Box 2, Item 47)
    Work number: 47_01
    Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856
    Symphonies, no. 4, op. 120, D minor
    Transcribed title: Symphony no. 4 in D minor, op. 120
    Performers: Philharmonia Orchestra; Guido Cantelli, conductor
    Work number: 47_02
    Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883
    Siegfried-Idyll
    Transcribed title: Siegfried Idyll
  - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 48, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: His Master's Voice: LHMV 18, Unknown Side 1 matrix: E4RP 8533; Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: unknown Looks like commercial release rather than test pressing; program notes inserted (Box 2, Item 48)
    Work number: 48_01
    Carnaval
    Transcribed title: Carnaval, op. 9
    Performers: Alfred Cortot, piano
    Work number: 48_02
    Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849
    Sonatas, piano, no. 2, op. 35, B♭ minor
    Transcribed title: Sonata no. 2 in B flat minor, op. 35
  - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 49, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: London: LL.1283, 1955 Side 1 matrix: ARL-2647-4A; Side 2 matrix: ARL 2647-4A Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: unknown This looks like the commercial release rather than a test pressing. (Box 2, Item 49)
    Work number: 49_02
    Romeo et Juliette (Fantasy-overture)
    Transcribed title: Romeo and Juliet: Fantasy overture
    Performers: Vienna Philharmonic Orchestra; Rafael Kubelik, conductor
    Work number: 49_01
    Slovanské tance, op. 46. Selections
    Transcribed title: Slavonic dances: Set 1 (no. 1-5)
  - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 50, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: London: LL.1284, 1955 Side 1 matrix: ARL 2645-1A; Side 2 matrix: ARL 2646-1A Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: unknown Contains dances from op. 46 (no. 6-8) and op. 72 (no. 1-8). This looks like the commercial release rather than a test pressing. (Box 2, Item 50)
    Work number: 50_01
    Slovanské tance. Selections
    Transcribed title: Slavonic dances
  - Mischa Schneider Collection Disc 51, undated, 1 33 rpm sound disc; 12 inches (2 sides); Released on: Unpublished: Not applicable, Not applicable Side 1 matrix: none; Side 2 matrix: none Pressing company: Unknown Date of recording: April 13 1950 Label: "Order no. LWO 1518" Library of Congress Music Division Recording Laboratory. 78 rpm. In poor condition. (Box 1, Item 51)
    Work number: 51_01
    Schneider, Mischa, 1903-1985 (interviewee)
    Interview of Mischa Schneider by Luther Evans, Part 1 of 3
    Transcribed title: Dr. Evans and Mischa Schneider recorded 4/11/50 for WQQW broadcast on 4/13/50
    Performers: Mischa Schneider, Luther Evans
- Music in the Air scripts, circa 1953, IV.; Item 52
  Arranged in numerical order.
  Four printed scripts for the announcer of the radio show, Music in the Air, featuring Columbia Records. A few of the recordings mentioned in the scripts are contained in the collection.
  - Music in the air scripts, numbers 6-9, circa 1953, 1 folder ( 4 scripts) (Box 2, Item 52)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Contributors
Budapest String Quartet; Columbia Records, Inc.; Marlboro Recording Society
Subjects
String quartets (Musical groups); Schneider, Mischa, 1903-1985
Genres
Sound recordings; Interviews